DMYTRO TELNOV

Web Developer

📞 +1 403-837-0700 @ detelnov@gmail.com 🔗 https://www.linkedin.com/in/dtlnv/ 🔗 https://github.com/dtlnv 👂 Calgary, AB

SUMMARY

Experienced web developer with frontend and backend development expertise. Capable of developing scalable, secure, and user-friendly web applications and websites, as well as of solving complex problems, learning quickly, and adapting to new technologies. Switched to JavaScript in 2019 after 5+ years of PHP development experience, continuing to expand skill set.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend JavaScript Engineer

Capgemini 04/2021 - Present Remote

capgemini.com

- Develop and improve Chrome Extensions focused on data encryption/decryption and digital privacy.
- Implement new modules and support existing ones by refactoring, bug fixing, and creating unit tests, maintaining high levels of code quality and performance.
- Stack: JavaScript, React.js, HTML, SASS/SCSS, Git, Browser Extensions, Service Workers, Google API, Google Cloud Platform, Webpack.

JavaScript Developer

Avtor LLC 04/2020 - 04/2021 Kyiv, Ukraine (Remote)

avtor.ua

- · Participated in the design and planning of web development projects.
- · Built an internal frontend library with reusable React components.
- Created unique web applications from scratch using the latest JavaScript frameworks and technologies, including React.js, SASS/SCSS, Next.js, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Figma and Git/GitHub.
- Fixed bugs, refactored legacy code, implemented improvements to enhance projects efficiency.
- Mentored and guided junior developers, sharing expertise, and creating documentation for the code base.

Technical Reviewer, Web Developer

TemplateMonster 03/2017 - 03/2020 Mykolaiv, Ukraine

templatemonster.com

- Performed comprehensive design and code reviews for CMS, eCommerce, HTML, and Graphic templates, examined product information, verified documentation, and detected plagiarized templates.
- Trained new technical reviewers and created a handbook with best review practices, contributing to the knowledge base and promoting consistent review standards.
- Developed tools, parsers and code checkers using React.js, PHP, Node.js and MySQL.
- $\cdot\;$ Created a Chrome Extension to expedite the review process.
- · Designed and implemented a database management system for vendors.
- All of these tools greatly increased the department's efficiency, streamlined the review processes and automated manual tasks.

VOLUNTEERING

Web Developer and Project Creator

Mykolaiv School №46

12/2019 - 05/2020 Mykolaiv, Ukraine

- · Developed a school web portal for remote learning during the pandemic.
- Designed and implemented a platform for teachers to manage class schedules, maintain blogs, and assign homework.
- Created a secure and user-friendly interface for students and parents to access information and resources.
- Utilized React.js, SASS/SCSS, Next.js, Node.js, Express.js, and MySQL to build a scalable and performant web application.
- · To learn more about the project, please visit 46.com.ua.

EDUCATION

Bachelor degree in Computer engineering (Evaluated by WES Canada)

V.O. Sukhomlynsky National University of Mykolaiv

09/2012 - 06/2015 Mykolaiv, Ukraine

SKILLS

Key Skills

API Integration		Browser Extensions		css
DOM	Express.js	Figma	Git	Github
HTML	JavaScript	JSON	Next.js	
Node.js	React.js	REST AP	REST API SASS	
scss	TypeScript	:		
Additional Skills				
Agile Methodologies Backend Development				
Code Review				
Content Management Systems (CMS)				
Databases Debugging				
Frontend Development GitHub Actions (GHA)				
Google API Google Cloud Platform (GCP)				
JQuery NPM MySQL PHP				
PostgreSQL React Native Redux				
Refactoring Search Engine Optimization (SEO)				
Service Workers Unit Tests				
User Interface/Experience (UI/UX) Vue.js				
Web Programming Web Security Webpack				
Website Building Website Maintenance				e Yarn